<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- AppStream metadata required by Flathub. Validate with:
     appstreamcli validate data/io.github.dibbayajyotiroy.Fresco.metainfo.xml -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.dibbayajyotiroy.Fresco</id>

  <name>Fresco</name>
  <summary>Set videos and images as live wallpapers</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      Fresco turns videos, GIFs, images, slideshows, and video playlists into
      your desktop wallpaper. Pick media in a simple app, click Set, then close
      the app — the wallpaper keeps playing and is restored on login.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Looping video, animated GIF, static image, image slideshow, and video playlist wallpapers</li>
      <li>Hardware-accelerated playback (VA-API / NVDEC) for low CPU usage without quality loss</li>
      <li>A drag-to-crop and 90-degree rotate editor to frame exactly the region you want</li>
      <li>Per-wallpaper sound and volume, plus slideshow transitions (crossfade, fade, slide, Ken Burns)</li>
      <li>A wallpaper library with thumbnails, a recently-used row, and search</li>
      <li>Pause / resume, pause-on-battery, and auto-pause when a window goes fullscreen</li>
      <li>Multi-monitor support with per-display wallpapers and synced video playback</li>
      <li>Add from a link: paste a Pinterest pin or a direct video/image URL</li>
      <li>Day and night wallpaper schedules</li>
      <li>A curated in-app wallpaper catalog</li>
      <li>A command palette (Ctrl+K) for fast keyboard-driven control</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Fresco runs on X11 and on Wayland layer-shell compositors (COSMIC,
      Hyprland, Sway, KDE Plasma 6); GNOME on Wayland uses a static-frame
      fallback.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.dibbayajyotiroy.Fresco.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DibbayajyotiRoy/fresco/main/data/screenshots/gallery.png</image>
      <caption>The wallpaper library</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/DibbayajyotiRoy/fresco</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/DibbayajyotiRoy/fresco/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/DibbayajyotiRoy/fresco</url>

  <developer id="io.github.dibbayajyotiroy">
    <name>Dibbayajyoti Roy</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#d76d77</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#3a1c71</color>
  </branding>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.1" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Live wallpapers now work on Ubuntu 24.04-based systems (COSMIC, Pop!_OS 24.04, Mint 22): Fresco ships one renderer per libmpv generation and picks the right one automatically. Also: paste a Pinterest or direct media link to add a wallpaper, a media-first redesign with rich metadata cards and favorites, a Ctrl+K command palette, an optional browser new-tab wallpaper bridge with a companion extension, self-finishing in-app updates, and anonymous opt-out usage statistics (disclosed in-app).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Multi-monitor video sync, schedule rotation fixes, smoother Wayland frame timing, and optional feedback reminders.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-07-04">
      <description>
        <p>Rotation polish: card thumbnails follow the edited rotation; hover previews no longer play in the wrong orientation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-07-03">
      <description>
        <p>Reliable per-wallpaper sound, pixel-true 4K/8K quality, an in-app wallpaper catalog, per-display wallpapers, day/night schedules, add-from-URL, and X11 fullscreen auto-pause.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.91" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>In-app updates with live progress, responsive layout, and a live status pill.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.9" date="2026-06-27">
      <description>
        <p>Rotate wallpapers, reliable per-wallpaper sound, native Wayland layer-shell probe.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.8" date="2026-06-26">
      <description>
        <p>Restore-on-login self-heal and cold-boot playback recovery.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.7" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>Wayland layer-shell support, fullscreen auto-pause, update notifications.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.2" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Bug-fix release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a freeze/crash when changing the wallpaper.</li>
          <li>Add and Add Folder now work; the file dialog shows videos and images by default.</li>
          <li>The GNOME overview and lock screen now match the live wallpaper.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.1" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
